NZ Citizen. Korea F5 visa. Kor: Tel: +82(0)10-5136-5543 Portfolio Email Linkedin Github

# **Objectives**

As a recent entrant into the field of software development, my ideal role would be in web development. I enjoy the process and seeing an entire project come together. I am also interested in data analytics and processing. I know the path ahead will be challenging and I look forward to putting in the hard work with a great team and organisation.

# **Skills Summary**

I have hands-on experience with Node.js and JavaScript-based programming, along with proficiency in React, REST API, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Docker, Node, Supertest, Jest, Express, HTML, CSS, BigQuery, R Programming, and SQL. I have worked with Agile development methodologies and have experience deploying applications on platforms like Heroku and Render.

#### **Projects**

- Le Seau a Boue <a href="https://lsbfront.onrender.com/">https://lsbfront.onrender.com/</a>. A responsive ecommerce site that showcases furniture, allowing users to sort them by rooms, and providing information such as price and cleaning instructions and is integrated with Stripe. Built with Stripe, Node, Express, React, Javascript, Insomnia, HTML, CSS, Canva, and Figma.
- EVolution <a href="https://ev-front.onrender.com/">https://ev-front.onrender.com/</a>. A responsive site that showcases the latest electric vehicles, allowing users to sort them by maker, and providing information such as the first year the vehicle was made, price, country, charging speed, and range on a full charge. Built using the PERN stack, JavaScript, and CSS.
- Gengar's Eats <a href="https://gengar-app-front.onrender.com/">https://gengar-app-front.onrender.com/</a>. This app was created with a MERN(MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) stack, with the purpose of letting users make a reservation at a restaurant. It allows users to view restaurants and uses Auth0 to allow registered users to log in and book restaurants at the time and date of their choosing and then view a list of their upcoming reservations. It was made responsive for mobiles and desktops.
- aY Sweets!. In this CRUD PERN (PostgreSQL, Express, React, Node) stack project, Javascript, Docker, and CSS modules were used to display a DB of products and allowed users to add their own suggestions and update the current database. This app was deployed using Render.com and is responsive for mobile and desktop.

- KPS Concept <a href="https://timely-licorice-172925.netlify.app/">https://timely-licorice-172925.netlify.app/</a>. This landing page was done as a challenge by my supervisor to improve the English language landing page for KEPCO KPS. Here is the current English language landing page <a href="https://www.kps.co.kr/eng/index.do">https://www.kps.co.kr/eng/index.do</a>. Continuous feedback was received and implemented during the process. This site was created using Javascript and CSS.
- **Energy Information Landing Page Concept.** This landing page was created with the purpose of providing information on current electricity trends and types, especially nuclear energy. Continuous feedback was received and implemented during the process. This site was created using Javascript and CSS.

#### **Educational Projects**

- Online Shop. In the creation of the online shop, Javascript,
  CSS, and a Stripe API that was created, were used to set up a simple online shop to help my understanding of APIs.
- Restaurant Reservation site. In this project Mongo DB, Express, APIs, React, Javascript, and CSS were used to create an app that included TDD using Express and Supertest, filtering, routes, API calls and endpoints that could be used to make reservations. This project also called for the use of Heroku and Netlify for deployment, and Auth0 for security.
- Online Shop. In this project React, Express, Auth0, API, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Docker, CSS modules, Supertest, Jest, Swagger, Stoplight were used to create an app that displayed a DB of products and used Pagination and Responsiveness for users convenience. This app was deployed using Render.com.
- Q & A App. In this project our team used an Agile Development approach using Jira and Miro for our Team charter, Lean UX design studio, Wireframes, User stories, ERD, and Kanban board. To implement the CRUD application, React, JS, CSS, Render, Github Actions CI/CD, DOCKER, NodeJS, Express, and PostgreSQL were used to create an app that allowed students to ask or answer development questions, and teachers to update or delete Q&As. In addition, Auth0 was used to control access and secure data.

#### Additional Information:

In addition to my software development experience, I have a background in Occupational Health and Safety and English as a Second Language. I possess strong skills in teamwork, communication, and honesty, which have helped me generate positive outcomes and improve opportunities for growth and development at a variety of companies, from multinational corporations to small startups.

# **Experience**

# ESL Coach 2016-2021 Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power and Korea Plant Services (KPS)

Duties included teaching conversation, grammar, IELTS, TOEIC Speaking and TOEIC to employees. Assisted students both in class and online, to help improve TOEIC and TOEIC Speaking scores for promotions, overseas projects, and personal goals.

# **ESL Coach 2016 Various larger corporations**

Free talking, business English, presentation, and debate. Assisted students with grammar, IELTS, TOEIC Speaking and TOEIC. In addition, examining cultural differences when doing business was a core part of their development.

**ESL Coach 2014-2015 Goyang City Community English Program** Teaching ESL to 1<sup>st</sup> through 6<sup>th</sup> grade and adults. As part of a community lead program funded by the government, I was responsible for teaching English to primary school students and adults.

**ESL Coach 2011-2013 Nanhyang Elementary School and Nangok Elementary School** – Afterschool Program For grades 1-6 ESL phonics, reading, and speaking.

#### Manager 2002-2010 MCO Trading

As part of my duties, I was responsible for organizing contracts and finances for overseas exports of Korean products ranging from vehicles to cosmetics. Assisted in the logistics of exports.

## Language Content Developer 2002 Aug-2003 May: S & J Wizard

Duties include paragraph, essay and dialogue writing for English language textbooks for foreign language high schools in Korea. Editing of final product. Assisting with printing design and layout of final products.

English Editor / Instructor 1999 Jun -2001 Apr: Daekyo Noonoppi Duties included writing and voice recording for English educational products. Content edition and revision of other writers' work, as well as final product revision.

#### Freelancer ESL Coach

Corporate classes: Yuhan Kimberly, Hyundai Engineering, Samsung C&T, Samsung Electronics, LG Chem, LG ENG, Hitel, Pricewaterhouse Coopers, Amkor, Innocean, Hanhwa, Standard Chartered Bank, CJ Media, Oracle, Daekyo, Hana Bank(Seoul Bank). Free talking, business English, presentation, and debate. Assisted students with grammar, IELTS, TOEIC Speaking and TOEIC. In addition, examining cultural differences when doing business was a core part of their development.

# **Education** Massey University - Palmerston North

Bachelor of Health Science with a focus in Occupational Health and Safety (OHS)/ Health, Safety, and Environment (HSE)

## **Developers Institute - Whangarei**

New Zealand Diploma in Web Design and Development Level 5 02/ 2022 - 12/ 2022

# **Google Data Analytics Certificate**

Cousera 2023

#### **Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals**

Microsoft 2022

**Languages** Native English speaker, Beginner Spanish, Intermediate Korean.

Interests Music: learning guitar/piano listening to music

Sports: golf, trekking, swimming

Travel

Electronics/ Technology

**References** Available on request:

Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power Victor Kum - Senior manager

**KEPCO-KPS (Korea Plant Services)** 

Young Bok Eom - Vice president/ Site manager